

AYESHA BAIG

DIRECTOR PRE-SCHOOL

I'm a Preschool Educationist with **28 years** of rich experience in this field. My endeavor is to create passionate early childhood teachers who facilitate a transformational positive impact on young minds. Truly committed to the field of Early years.

I conducted several **training programs**, **seminars**, and **workshops** for Heads, School Teachers, Anganwadi Teachers & NGOs.

As a teacher trainer, I was heading a leading teacher training institute in Mumbai and was an adjunct faculty at Asian International College, Singapore's Indian venture. Currently, I am working as Director Preschool.

EDUCATION

SNDT Women's University - M.A.Ed-Education Management: 2009 - 2011

Mithibai College - Bachelors of Arts: 1994 - 1995

https://bit.ly/ayeshabaig

Mithibai College - Higher Secondary Certificate: 1990 - 1991

Gyan Kendra High School - Secondary School Certificate: 1988 - 1989

EDUCATIONAL CERTIFICATIONS

Asian International College - International Certificate in Education Preschool Teaching: 2015 - 2016

University of Mumbai - Early Childhood Care & Education: 1993 - 1994

EXPERIENCE

- Indus Altum Early Learning Centre Director Preschool
 June 2018 Current
- Childern's Academy Group of Schools Academic Head
 February 2013 May 2018
- Excelsis Teacher Training Institute (ETTI) Head of Centre
 June 2017 May 2018
- Excelsis Teacher Training Institute Head of Content & Curriculum Development September 2017 - May 2018
- Asian International College Adjunct Faculty January 2015 - January 2017
- Early Childhood Association (ECA) Head of Mumbai Territory
 February 2013 2018

• Podar Jumbo Kids - Executive Head

June 2011 - November 2012

 Childern's Academy Group of Schools - Pre-primary Headmistress March 2007 - May 2011

• **Welspun School** – Educational Consultant, Syllabus Designer & Teacher Trainer January 2006 – February 2007

AREAS OF EXPERTISE

- Conducted Training workshops, Seminars for Heads, Principals, School teachers, Anganwadi teachers & NGOs in association with ECA & AECED
- Writing articles on parenting, & conducting summer camps.
- Conducting in-depth workshops for teachers on Music and movement, Pedagogy, Good children Bad behavior, Enhancing Creativity, Turning the searchlight inward, thinking out of the box, Bridging Teaching - Learning Process at Preschool through Assessment, & Time management.
- Expertise in providing training on Conflict Management, Personality Development,
 Classroom Management, Language & Communication Skills, Phonetics Jolly Phonics,
 Connecting Children to Nature, & Phonetics Floppy Phonics

PUBLICATIONS

Books:

- Periwinkle, Blossom Series, *Math Workbooks*, Level 1 & 2, Jeevandeep
- Periwinkle, Blossom Series, *Activity Workbooks*, Level 1, 2, & 3, Jeevandeep
- Periwinkle, Blossom Series, Pattern Writing Workbooks, Level 1, Jeevandeep

AWARDS & ACHIEVEMENTS

8th International Conference of Pre-primary and Primary Principals - 3rd place for a Paper presentation on 'Experiential Learning' 2017

Education World India -

Award for Extraordinary Leadership 2018-2019

Childern's Academy Group of Schools -

- Ranked No.10 in Maharashtra by India Preschool ranking by Education World India 2015 2016
- Ranked No.6 for Developmentally Appropriate Curriculum Planning and assessment by Early Childhood Association 2016 - 2017

Indus Altum Early Learning Centre -

Ranked as No. 1 Preschool by Education World India 2018–2019

Indus Altum Early Learning Centre -

•	Future Ready Preschool by Education World India	2019 - 2020
•	Innovative Pedology by Education World India	2020 - 2021
•	Future Ready Preschool by Education World India	2021 - 2022

India Didactics Association -

The International Education & Skill Summit (TIESS 2022) - Speaker at the Round table discussion

REFERENCES

- 1. Dr. Swati Popat Vats President Podar Jumbo Kids.
- 2. Mrs. Asha Varma Ex-Chief Coordinator Children's Academy Group of Schools.